gov.im 2019-07-14

# Isle of Man Government - Privacy notice

This Privacy Notice applies to the Isle of Man Government website which is owned by the Cabinet Office. We recommend you take some time to read this notice and if you do not agree to this privacy notice please do not provide us with your personal information. 

When you use an Isle of Man Government service over the internet we may ask you to share personal information with us.

When we collect your personal information we will:

  * only collect what we need and no more
  * keep your information secure
  * tell you how we will use your information
  * delete your information when it is no longer needed
  * only process your information in line with rules set out in the [Data Protection Act 2018](https://legislation.gov.im/cms/images/LEGISLATION/PRINCIPAL/2018/2018-0010/DataProtectionAct2018_1.pdf)

When you give personal information the Privacy Notice of the Department, Board or Office that collects the information will explain:

  * What information is collected and why
  * Who is collecting it
  * How it is collected
  * Why it is being collected
  * How it will be used
  * How long it will be kept
  * Who it will be shared with
  * How that information will be kept secure
  * Your choices, including how to access and update information

This notice may be replaced, or more information added, when you use a specific service. For example if you file a Tax Return, pay your Rate Demand or apply for a Driving Theory Test, information about the provider of that service and your rights will be available. 

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy we will post changes to this Privacy Notice. If you have any questions or comments on this Privacy Notice please email the Cabinet Office Data Protection Officer. 

Contact the Data Protection Officer for the Cabinet Office:

Email: [DPO-CabOff@gov.im](mailto:DPO-CabOff@gov.im "Cabinet Office DPO")  

Phone: +44 1624 686779

Postal address: DPO, Cabinet Office, Government Office, Buck's Road, Douglas, IM1 3PN, Isle of Man, British Isles

## How and why we ask you to share your personal information

We collect and process information, including personal information, to provide effective and efficient services.

We use your personal information in line with the rules set out in the [Data Protection Act 2018](https://legislation.gov.im/cms/images/LEGISLATION/PRINCIPAL/2018/2018-0010/DataProtectionAct2018_1.pdf) for the following reasons:

  * Where you have agreed to the process
  * To allow Government Departments, Boards and Offices to communicate with you
  * To process payments you make
  * To give you a single Government account to access online services
  * To provide access to other services provided by Government Departments, Boards and Offices online
  * To analyse use of the website and make improvements 

## Our legal basis for processing your information

We will only process your personal information if there is a legal reason for us to do so. We may rely on:

  * Your consent – if we rely on your consent to process your information you may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting the Data Protection Officer for the relevant part of government 
  * The need to meet a legal obligation in carrying out statutory government functions
  * The need to meet a request you have made for information or a service
  * The need to prevent or investigate suspected or actual violations of law
  * The need to protect  public interest
  * The need to retain information for historical or archiving purposes by the Public Record Office under the Public Records Act 1999 – more information on retention is available from the Public Record Office

## Types of personal information we collect about you

Depending on how you interact with us we may process different information about you. Below you will find an overview of the categories of information that we may collect.

If you use a link to any website operated by a Department or Office of the Isle of Man Government, or any external website, you should make sure you read the privacy policy or fair processing notice on that website page to find out what it does with your information.

## Information you provide to us directly

Category of information

| 

Examples of that type of information  
  
---|---  
  
Account login information

| 

Login ID, password, or security questions  
  
Contact information

| 

Name, email address, telephone number, address  
  
Financial information

| 

Invoice number, amount

**We do not hold credit or debit card information**  
  
Government identifiers

| 

Driving licence number, NHS number, national insurance number  
  
Health information

| 

General symptoms, source of pain, diagnosis  
  
Other information

| 

Feedback, comments, complaints  
  
Personal identification information

| 

Name, title, data of birth  
  
## Information we collect automatically

When you visit or use our website we may collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone, or other device. For example we may collect:

Category of information

| 

Examples of that type of information  
  
---|---  
  
Device information

| 

Hardware model, operating system version  
  
Log information

| 

Time and duration of visit  
  
Other information

| 

Links you click, location  
  
Tracking information

| 

When you visit this site we use cookies that do not collect any personal information.

Read more about how we use Cookies  
  
## How long do we keep your personal information

We will only keep your information for the minimum time necessary.

This may be to:

  * To respond to an enquiry from you
  * To continue to give you access to a service you have requested that is provided by another Department, Board or Office
  * Confirm the transfer of information to the Department, Office or Board providing a service you have requested

## How we keep your personal information secure

The security and confidentiality of your information is very important to us.

We will ensure that:

  * Safeguards are in place to make sure personal information is kept securely
  * Only hold your information on servers that are under the control of the Cabinet Office and within the jurisdiction of the Isle of Man
  * Only authorised staff are able to view your information
  * Maintain security of the systems which hold personal information in line with ISO27001 standard
  * We comply with the requirements of the PCI Security Standards Council

We may share your information:

  * With or between other Government Departments, Boards and Offices to provide a service or information you have requested
  * The police or law enforcement agencies where there is a legal requirement to do so
  * The courts on production of a valid court order

We will not sell to, or share, your personal information with other companies, organisations or individuals.

Individual Departments may share your personal information with other companies, organisations or individuals where there is a legal requirement to do so.

Your personal information will not be disclosed to any third party without your prior consent or where required to do so by law.

## What are your rights?

###  **To ask if we hold personal information about you**

You can ask to see what information we hold about you by submitting a Subject Access Request to the Cabinet Office Data Protection Officer.

### You can review your personal information and ensure it is accurate

Where possible we will provide you with access to the information we hold about you so that you can view this information and provide a means for you to have this information changed if it is not accurate.

Alternatively you can ask for the information we hold about you to be changed by making a request to the Cabinet Office Data Protection Officer.

### **To remove your personal information**

In certain circumstances you can ask for your information to be deleted. Please note that as part of the Isle of Man Government statutory functions some information may need to be retained.

You can request this by contacting the Cabinet Office Data Protection Officer.

### To make a complaint

If you are unhappy with the way we deal with your personal information you can submit a complaint to the Cabinet Office Data Protection Officer who will work with you to resolve any issues.

The Information Commissioner is the independent authority responsible for upholding the public's information rights and promoting and enforcing compliance with the Island's information rights legislation. Further information can be found on the [Information Commissioner's website](https://www.inforights.im/).

You have the right to request the Information Commissioner to undertake an assessment as to whether the processing of your personal data has been carried out in accordance with the provisions of the [Data Protection Act 2018](https://legislation.gov.im/cms/images/LEGISLATION/PRINCIPAL/2018/2018-0010/DataProtectionAct2018_1.pdf). 

### **Contact details**

**Data Protection Officer of the Cabinet Office**

Email address: [DPO-CabOff@gov.im](mailto:DPO-CabOff@gov.im "Cabinet Office DPO")

Telephone: +44 1624 686779

Postal address:

DPO, Cabinet Office  
Government Office  
Buck's Road  
Douglas  
Isle of Man  
IM1 3PN

## Will this privacy notice change

This Privacy Notice may change. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Notice without your consent. If any significant change is made to this Privacy Notice we will provide a prominent notice on this website so that you can review the updated Privacy Notice. 

This Privacy Notice may be replaced, or more information added, when you send feedback, ask to use a service online or make a payment for a service through this website. For example when you file Tax Return information specific to that service will be made available to you.

This privacy notice was last updated in August 2018.

## How to request access to your personal information

Under the [Data Protection Act 2018](https://legislation.gov.im/cms/images/LEGISLATION/PRINCIPAL/2018/2018-0010/DataProtectionAct2018_1.pdf), you have a right of access to your personal data and to check the accuracy of that data by making a  **Subject Access Request**.

A subject access request is made by contacting the Data Protection Officer (DPO) of the Department, Office or Board that collects the information.

To make a request of the DPO for the Cabinet Office contact:

DPO, Cabinet Office  
Government Office  
Buck's Road  
Douglas  
Isle of Man  
IM1 3PN

Email: [DPO-CabOff@gov.im](mailto:DPO-CabOff@gov.im)  
Phone: +44 1624 686779

In certain circumstances a charge may apply.

Subject access requests must be responded to promptly and in any event within a maximum of 1 month.

The Information Commissioner is the independent authority responsible for upholding the public's information rights and promoting and enforcing compliance with the Island's information rights legislation. Further information can be found on the [Information Commissioner's website](https://www.inforights.im/).

You have the right to request the Information Commissioner to undertake an assessment as to whether the processing of your personal data has been carried out in accordance with the provisions of the [Data Protection Act 2018](https://legislation.gov.im/cms/images/LEGISLATION/PRINCIPAL/2018/2018-0010/DataProtectionAct2018_1.pdf).
